

2524 Sandy Ridge Lane Charlotte, North Carolina, 28105 abreckwoldt23@gmail.com 704-618-7423 Website: https://www.awoldt.com/

Website: https://www.awoldt.com/ GitHub: https://github.com/awoldt

My name is Alex Breckwoldt, and I'm a full-stack developer from Charlotte, NC. Over the past five years, I have taught myself the fundamentals of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. After getting the basics down, I moved on to learning Node.js, where my interest in coding took off. I deeply understand OOP programming and can adapt to any tech stack needed. Now I focus on building a name for myself and working on personal projects that interest me in my free time. My goal is to one day have a job in the tech industry and build tools that help people's lives.

Professional Experience

Package Handler Amazon | November 2019 - August 2021

At Amazon, I ensured that all packages that passed through the warehouse went to the correct spot and got to the customer on time. I worked at Amazon over the course of 3 years and learned a lot about how a significant company with thousands of moving parts operates.

Cashier Circle K | May 2019 - August 2019

At Circle K, I was tasked with checking out people efficiently and politely. Working at Circle K helped me establish customer skills and communication.

Kennel Assistant Monroe Road Animal Hospital | June 2015 - August 2015

Monroe Road Animal Hospital was the first formal job I ever had. I ensured all the dogs and cats boarding with us had an optimal living space and enough food and water.

Education

High School Diploma Butler High School at Matthews | August 2012 - June 2016

Bachelors in Management Information Systems University of North Carolina at Charlotte | August 2016- May 2022

Key Skills

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- Node.js
- React.js
- Next.js
- Express.js
- Google Cloud Platform
- Firebase
- MongoDB

Personal Projects

Below are some of the best personal projects I've worked on that showcase my front-end and back-end development skills. You can find a complete list of all my projects on my GitHub.

<u>StockWasp</u> - Fully-fledged stock price and news web app built on Express.js and styled with Bootstrap. Fetches real-time stock data on each request using Financial Modeling Prep's API.

https://stockwasp.com/

<u>WordleBin</u> - Remake of the popular web game Wordle. Complex React.js front-end with the option to create custom games to share with friends. It uses Firebase as a database in the back-end to store all these games.

https://wordlebin.com/

Spotify Music Dashboard - Sign in to your Spotify account and visualize all your favorite music and artists on one page, along with music recommendations.

https://spotify-dashboard-ruby.vercel.app/

<u>Popular Tweet Filter</u>- Lookup any public Twitter profile and filter their tweets by most likes, retweets, and comments. <u>https://tweets-filter.vercel.app/</u>